<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Audit fees | Manyi Fan</title>
    <link>/tags/audit-fees/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/audit-fees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Audit fees</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Audit fees</title>
      <link>/tags/audit-fees/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Consequences of Allowing Auditors Domiciled in Weak Institutional Environments to Audit Firms Cross-listed in Strong Institutional Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/two-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/two-head/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examine the consequences of a Hong Kong regulation change in 2010 that allowed companies incorporated in mainland China and cross-listed in Hong Kong (H share companies) to hire mainland Chinese auditors for the purposes of Hong Kong financial reporting. Before the regulation change, the financial statements of the H share companies must be audited by Hong Kong domiciled auditors. H share companies were more likely to switch to mainland auditors if they expected larger audit fee saving and lower equity financing needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the majority of the H share companies continued to employ Hong Kong auditors after the regulation change. The H share companies as a whole experienced a decline in both audit fees and audit quality. The audit fee decline is solely driven by the switchers while the audit quality decline is attributed to both the switchers and non-switchers. This latter finding suggests that the entry of mainland Chinese auditors created a competitive pressure on the incumbent Hong Kong auditors, resulting in a race to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
