<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regulation | Manyi Fan</title>
    <link>/tags/regulation/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Regulation</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Regulation</title>
      <link>/tags/regulation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Consequences of Allowing Auditors Domiciled in Weak Institutional Environments to Audit Firms Cross-listed in Strong Institutional Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/two-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/two-head/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cross listing has been a popular mechanism through which firms domiciled in home countries with weak investor protection raise equity capital from investors domiciled in host countries with strong investor protection. Due to severe information asymmetry between cross-listed firms and their investors in the host countries, audit firms have been one of the critical gatekeepers in safeguarding the interests of cross-listed firms’ investors. Accordingly, securities regulators around the world have spent considerable resources in regulating the behavior of cross-listed firms’ auditors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examine the consequences of a Hong Kong regulation change in 2010 that allowed companies incorporated in mainland China and cross-listed in Hong Kong (H share companies) to hire mainland Chinese auditors for the purposes of Hong Kong financial reporting. Before the regulation change, the financial statements of the H share companies must be audited by Hong Kong domiciled auditors. H share companies were more likely to switch to mainland auditors if they expected larger audit fee saving and lower equity financing needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the majority of the H share companies continued to employ Hong Kong auditors after the regulation change. The H share companies as a whole experienced a decline in both audit fees and audit quality. The audit fee decline is solely driven by the switchers while the audit quality decline is attributed to both the switchers and non-switchers. This latter finding suggests that the entry of mainland Chinese auditors created a competitive pressure on the incumbent Hong Kong auditors, resulting in a race to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
