<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Manyi Fan</title>
    <link>/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are auditors more conservative</title>
      <link>/publication/accounting-student/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/accounting-student/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examine whether and why auditors are more conservative than non-auditors. Based on a database of college graduates in one major Chinese university over the period 2004-2014, we track the career path of each student from the initial university enrollment in the accounting major all the way up to five years after joining the auditing profession. We measure conservatism using two proxies based on each student’s selection of general education elective courses in the university. We find that more conservative students are more likely to choose accounting as their major. However, we find no evidence that the accounting major students who are more conservative are more likely to become auditors. In addition, we find that the auditors who are more conservative are more likely to remain in the auditing profession five years after graduation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide a new explanation for the existence of accounting conservatism. The equilibrium choices of the individual auditors in the profession suggest that the group of auditors are inherently more conservative than non-auditors. Hence, accounting conservatism may exist independently of the institutional environment, such as contracting, litigation, regulation and taxation, as largely documented by the literature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Consequences of Allowing Auditors Domiciled in Weak Institutional Environments to Audit Firms Cross-listed in Strong Institutional Environments</title>
      <link>/publication/two-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/two-head/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We examine the consequences of a Hong Kong regulation change in 2010 that allowed companies incorporated in mainland China and cross-listed in Hong Kong (H share companies) to hire mainland Chinese auditors for the purposes of Hong Kong financial reporting. Before the regulation change, the financial statements of the H share companies must be audited by Hong Kong domiciled auditors. H share companies were more likely to switch to mainland auditors if they expected larger audit fee saving and lower equity financing needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the majority of the H share companies continued to employ Hong Kong auditors after the regulation change. The H share companies as a whole experienced a decline in both audit fees and audit quality. The audit fee decline is solely driven by the switchers while the audit quality decline is attributed to both the switchers and non-switchers. This latter finding suggests that the entry of mainland Chinese auditors created a competitive pressure on the incumbent Hong Kong auditors, resulting in a race to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleeplessness, Distraction and Stock Market Performance: Evidence from the World Cup</title>
      <link>/publication/world-cup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/world-cup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We study how sleeplessness and distraction impact global financial markets. Using the world&amp;rsquo;s most widely viewed sporting event, the FIFA World Cup, we uncover significantly negative stock returns due to the sleeplessness from watching the games overnight and the distraction from the games during trading hours. Both effects are stronger for countries with better soccer game records, and are independent of the sentiment effect due to game results documented in the literature.&lt;br /&gt;
We document negative sleeplessness and distraction effects, which are statistically significant and economically non-trivial. This may seem striking because financial professionals are used to working long hours and are less attention driven, but still suffer from sleeplessness and distraction. This suggests that firms should require managers and key personnel to avoid making important decisions around significant attention-grabbing events.  Our findings give rationales to the following practical managerial decisions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some US firms close down business to allow employees to attend to election rallies;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local governments in Brazil were given authority to decide if it should be a holiday, day-off, or other flexible arrangement during the World Cup games;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some firms have email rules not to communicate with colleagues and clients at night; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firms usually approve business travel class only for long-haul flights.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking News is Good News</title>
      <link>/publication/storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/storm/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientists have shown that humans and non-human animals can avoid choosing an obviously suboptimal choice. This optimal choice hypothesis forms the basis for the theory of rational choice in social science and economics, as well as behavioral ecology. However, many studies have shown that some animals, including pigeons and monkeys, would prefer a suboptimal choice in the presence of informative signals about upcoming reward. Recent studies suggest a potential neural mechanism in monkeys for the preference of informative signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since humans have not been shown to behave in this way in the laboratory or real world, it would be very difficult to show the impact of preference of informative signals on the behavior of humans, even if there is a similar neural mechanism for humans. To overcome the problem, we directly show that an informative signal leads to a significant impact on the financial market through a natural experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
